Capital District Reference; Collection mss157
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Capital District Reference Collection
1868-2005
Undated
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss157
15.13 cubic ft.
This collection was artificially assembled by University at Albany library staff in the mid to late 20th century to provide general reference information about cities, communities, and towns and various aspects of life in the Capital District of New York State.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
This collection was initially assembled and arranged by the library staff at the University at Albany sometime in the mid to late 20th Century. The exact date or year of initial creation is unknown. The exact manner in which the department of special collections and archives acquired the collection is also unknown, but its likely that library staff simply moved the collection from the library's main collections to those of special collections and archives.
Arrangement of Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are and no series.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
This collection was initially assembled by library staff at the University at Albany sometimes in the mid 20th century and was later added to by library and archival staff over time until 2005. The vast majority of the newspaper clippings in the collection date from the 1950s to the early 1908s, and the bulk of them span the period from 1977 to 1981.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of reference materials primarily concerning cities, communities, towns and various aspects of life in the Capital District of New York State but also contains items concerning other regions of the state, including the Adirondacks, Buffalo, New York City, and Ulster County. The archivist has defined the Capital District as consisting of Albany, Columbia, Fulton, Greene, Montgomery, Rensselaer, Saratoga, Schenectady, Schoharie, Warren, and Washington Counties.
The collection primarily consists of newspapers and newspaper clippings but also includes advertisements, applications, art books, bank signets, booklets, book plates, brochures, bulletins, by-laws, catalogues, charts, circulars, city and community plans, club records, contracts, correspondence, digests, directions, directories, event flyers and programs, greeting cards, guides, histories of local communities and institutions, illustrations, information cards, instructions, lectures, lists, magazines and magazine clippings, maps, membership cards and forms, memoranda, monographs, newsletters, notices, photographs, political primers, posters, prints, proposals, reports, schedules, short biographies and descriptions, short publications, speeches, statements of condition, studies, and surveys. Finally, the collection contains materials pertaining to the Albany Times Union, such as audit reports, the organizations's by-laws and constitution, and a survey of employees' experience and wages from 1946.
Some newspapers articles in the collections are split between a folder and flat file, specificially those concerning Newburgh, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in Troy, and Schuylerville.
The vast majority of the materials are in English, but one of the items, which concerns the Spanish Center in Albany, is in Spanish.
Albany, New York; Schenectady, New York; Rensselaer County, New York; Albany County (N.Y.); Albany (N.Y.); Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.)
- 1800 Ulster County Gazette, Reproduction, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
- 1830 Albany Christian Register, Reproduction, 1954 (Oversized 2, Folder 1)
- Adirondacks, 1896; 1943-1953; 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adirondacks, Sacandaga Reservoir, 1963; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Adirondacks, Sky-Life Flying Camp, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Albany, 411 State Street, 1982 (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
- Albany, Academies, 1936-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Albany, Academies, 1938-1939; 1945 (Oversized 2, Folder 2)
- Albany and Rensselaer, Port (1 of 2), 1932-1981; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Albany and Rensselaer, Port (2 of 2), 1932-1981; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Albany and Rensselaer, Port, 1936-1937; 1939; 1950 (Oversized 2, Folder 3)
- Albany and Troy, Russell Sage College, 1960-1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Albany, Ann Lee Home, 1948; 1959; 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Albany Anvil, Democratic Socialists of America, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Albany, Arbor Hill, 1963-1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Albany Area Environmental Center, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Albany, Aurania Club, 1952; 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Albany, Baths, Public, 1961-1963; 1967; 1978; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Albany, Bicentennial Celebrations, 1886; 1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Albany, Boxing, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Albany, Brochures and Guides, 1953; 1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Albany, Building Codes, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Albany, Buildings, 1955; 1960-1961; 1963-1967; 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Albany, Buildings and Places, Historic, 1909-1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Albany, Buildings, Historic, Preservation, 1960-1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Albany, Buildings, Public, 1936-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Albany, Business and Industry, 1930-1981; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Albany, Business and Industry, 1941; 1956 (Oversized 2, Folder 4)
- Albany Business College, 1957; 1978-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Albany, Capital District Psychiatric Center, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Albany, Capitol Hill Architectural Review Commission, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Albany, Carillon Tower, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Albany, Census, 1957-1981; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Albany, Ceramics, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Albany Chamber of Commerce Education Committee, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Albany, Cherry Hill Mansion, 1949-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Albany Child Guidance Center, 1959-1960; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Albany City and County, Finances, Public, 1935-1981; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Albany City Arts Office, 1977-1979; 1983 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Albany, City Club, 1931-1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Albany City Hall, 1936-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Albany Civic Center, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Albany Club, 1938 (Oversized 2, Folder 5)
- Albany College of Pharmacy, 1977-1978; 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Albany, College of Saint Rose, 1955; 1959; 1962; 1966; 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Albany, Community Development, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Albany, Corning, Erastus II, 1968; 1970; 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Albany, Corning, Erastus II, 1978; 1983 (Oversized 2, Folder 6)
- Albany County Airport, 1955-1967; 1969; 1972-1974; 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Albany County Airport, 1978 (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
- Albany County Annual Report, 1975-1985; 1979-1989 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
- Albany County Annual Report, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Albany County ARC, 1963; 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Albany County at the Crossroads, Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Albany County Attorneys, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Albany County, Big Brothers and Big Sisters, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Albany County Charter, 1971-1974; 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Albany County, Civil Service, 1977; 1979 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Albany County, Cooperative Extension Association, 1971; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Albany County Coroner's Office, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Albany County Courthouse, 1962; 1964-1964; 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Albany County Department of Health, 1977; 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Albany County Department of Social Services, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Albany County, Drive-It-Yourself Tour, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Albany County, Dudley Observatory, 1936; 1966-1967; 1972; 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Albany County, Freedom of Information, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Albany County, Government and Politics, 1936; 1941 (Oversized 2, Folder 7)
- Albany County, Government and Politics (1 of 2), 1939-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Albany County, Government and Politics (2 of 2), 1939-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Albany County, Hudson-Champlain Celebration (1 of 3), 1937; 1957-1959; Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 8)
- Albany County, Hudson-Champlain Celebration (2 of 3), 1937; 1957-1959; Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 9)
- Albany County, Hudson-Champlain Celebration (3 of 3), 1937; 1957-1959; Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 10)
- Albany County, Hudson-Champlain Celebration, 1953; 1957-1960; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Albany County Jail, 1939 (Oversized 2, Folder 11)
- Albany County Jail (1 of 2), 1963-1981; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Albany County Jail (2 of 2), 1963-1981; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Albany County League of Women Voters, 1955-1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Albany County, Maps, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Albany County Opportunity, Inc., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Albany County Probation Department, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Albany County Rape Crisis Center, 1957; 1977-1981; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Albany County, Soils, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Albany County, Tri-Village Area, 1950 (Oversized 2, Folder 12)
- Albany, Courts of Appeals Building, 1950; 1957-1959; 1977-1978; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Albany, Cradle of the Union Celebration, 1939; 1947; 1953-1954; 1958; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Albany, Cradle of the Union Celebration, 1954 (Oversized 2, Folder 13)
- Albany, Cybernetics Institute, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Albany, Dana Natural History Society, 1958; 1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Albany, Delaware and Hudson Building, 1917; 1962; 1966; 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Albany Department of Human Resources, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Albany, Description, 1936; 1939 (Oversized 2, Folder 14)
- Albany, Dewey, Thomas Edmund, 1938; 1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Albany, Dewey, Thomas Edmund, 1938-1939; 1971 (Oversized 2, Folder 15)
- Albany, Doane Stuart School, 1959-1963; 1965; 1975-1976; 1978; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Albany, Dongan Charter, 1936-1937; 1971-1972; 1974; 1979; Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Albany, Dongan Charter, 250th Anniversary, 1936 (Oversized 2, Folder 16)
- Albany, Education, Vocational, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Albany, Egg, 1976-1981; 1988; Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Albany, Empire State Plaza (1 of 2), 1960; 1963-1967; 1969-1981; 1985; Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Albany, Empire State Plaza (2 of 2), 1960; 1963-1967; 1969-1981; 1985; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Albany, Empire State Youth Theater, 1976-1981; Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Albany Evening News, Education Edition, 1936 (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
- Albany Evening News, Rensselaer County, 1936-1937; Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 17)
- Albany Evening News, Rural Albany County, 1936; Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 18)
- Albany, Executive Mansion, 1936-1981; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Albany, Executive Mansion, 1936; 1958 (Oversized 2, Folder 19)
- Albany, Family and Children's Service, 1958; 1963; 1965; 1977 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Albany, Federal Highway Administration, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Albany, Fort Orange Club, 1956; 1960; 1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Albany, Fort Orange, Dig, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Albany, Freedom Sesquicentennial Celebration, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Albany, Gales, 1938; 1954 (Oversized 2, Folder 20)
- Albany, Government and Politics, 1936; 1938-1941 (Oversized 2, Folder 21)
- Albany, Government and Politics (1 of 2), 1938-1987; Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Albany, Government and Politics (2 of 2), 1938-1987; Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Albany, Great Decisions Forum, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Albany, Harmanus Bleecker Center for History and Art, 1948; 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Albany, Henry, Joseph, 1938 (Oversized 2, Folder 22)
- Albany, Herman Melville Week, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Albany, Historic Albany Foundation, 1977-1980; Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Albany, Historic Albany Foundation, 1979-1989 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
- Albany, Historic Sites Commission, 1961-1980; Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Albany, History, 17th and 18 Centuries, 1921; 1936; 1941; 1954-1955; 1958 (Oversized 2, Folder 23)
- Albany, History, 17th and 18th Centuries, 1936-1977; Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Albany, History, 19th Century (1 of 2), 1912-1988; Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Albany, History, 19th Century (2 of 2), 1912-1988; Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Albany, History, 19th Century, 1933; 1956; 1959-1961; Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 24)
- Albany, History, 20th Century, 1936-1977 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Albany, History, General, 1927; 1936; 1951; 1972 (Oversized 2, Folder 25)
- Albany, History, General, 1931-2002; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Albany Home for Children, 1954; 1956-1961; 1965; 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Albany, Hope House, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Albany, Hospitality House, 1977; 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Albany, House Art, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Albany, Housing (1 of 2), 1966; 1969-1974; 1977-1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Albany, Housing (2 of 2), 1966; 1969-1974; 1977-1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Albany, Hudson-Fulton Celebration, 1909; 1936-1937; 1962; 1964-1966; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Albany, Hudson Park Neighborhood Association, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Albany, Indoor Sports Club, 1954; 1956; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Albany Institute of History and Art (1 of 2), 1923-1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Albany Institute of History and Art (2 of 2), 1923-1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Albany Institute of History and Art, 1939 (Oversized 2, Folder 26)
- Albany International Center, 1957-1979; Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Albany Inter-Racial Council, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Albany, Jewish Community Center, 1960-1961; 1966; 1978; Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Albany, Junior College, 1959-1960; 1966; 1977-1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Albany, Junior League, 1957-1979; Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Albany, Lansing, Catherine Gansevoort, 1937 (Oversized 2, Folder 27)
- Albany Law School, 1936; 1962; 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Albany League of Art, 1977-1979; Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Albany Legal Aid Society, 1969-1970; 1977-1978; 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Albany, Maria College, 1966-1967; 1975; 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Albany Masonic Temple, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Albany Medical Center, 1939-1981; Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Albany Medical Center, 1941; 1955; 1957; Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 28)
- Albany Medical College, 1936-1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Albany, Medicine, History, 1936 (Oversized 2, Folder 29)
- Albany, Medicine, History, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Albany, Memorial Hospital, 1955-1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Albany, Mercy House, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Albany, Mildred Elley School, 1960; 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Albany, Military, 1936-1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Albany, Military, 1936; 1940 (Oversized 2, Folder 30)
- Albany Mirror, Voice of Poverty, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Albany, North End, 1959; 1964; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Albany, New York Eagles, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Albany, New York State Archives, 1977; Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Albany, New York State Capital, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Albany, New York State Capitol (1 of 2), 1905-1985; Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Albany, New York State Capitol (2 of 2), 1905-1985; Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Albany, New York State Capitol, 1929-1959; Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 31)
- Albany, New York State Education Building (1 of 2), 1908-1968; Undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Albany, New York State Education Building (2 of 2), 1908-1968; Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Albany, New York State Education Building, 1937 (Oversized 1, Folder 7)
- Albany, New York State Governor's Conference on Libraries, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Albany, New York State Library, 1911-1979; Undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Albany, New York State Library, Indigenous Peoples, 1954 (Oversized 2, Folder 32)
- Albany, New York State Museum (1 of 2), 1922-1984; Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Albany, New York State Museum (2 of 2), 1922-1984; Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Albany, New York State Museum, 1949; 1958 (Oversized 2, Folder 33)
- Albany, New York State Office Building, 1917 (Oversized 2, Folder 34)
- Albany, New York State Office Building, 1939-1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Albany, New York State Office Campus, 1948 (Oversized 1, Folder 8)
- Albany, New York State Office Campus, 1958; 1960-1967; 1970; Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Albany, Night Clubs, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Albany, Northeastern New York Speech Center, 1956; 1960; 1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Albany, Notable Visitors, 1973; 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Albany, O'Connell, Daniel Peter, 1959-1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Albany, Old Albany Calendar, 1973-1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Albany, Palais Royale, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Albany, Parents' and Children's Center, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Albany, Parsons Child and Family Center, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Albany, Pawnbrokers, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Albany, Philip Schuyler Senior High School, 1961-1973; Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Albany, Pigeons, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Albany, Pinebush Preservation, 1955; 1975-1976; 1978; 1983; Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Albany, Pine Hills, 1964; 1976; 1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Albany, Pinkerfest, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Albany, Police, 1936; 1956; 1958; 1965; 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Albany, Project Equinox, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Albany, Protests, 1969 (Oversized 2, Folder 35)
- Albany, Protests, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Albany, Public Libraries, 1937-1980; Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Albany, Quackenbush Square, 1936; 1961; 1965; 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Albany, Quackenbush Square, 1977-1979 (Oversized 2, Folder 36)
- Albany, Racial Unrest, 1967 (Oversized 2, Folder 37)
- Albany, RCA's Nipper, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Albany, Redlining, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Albany, Roads and Traffic, 1965-1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Albany, Robinson Square, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Albany School of Cytotechnology, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Albany, Schools, 1936-1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Albany, Schools, 1936 (Oversized 2, Folder 38)
- Albany, Schools, Public (1 of 3), 1933-1980; Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Albany, Schools, Public (2 of 3), 1933-1980; Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Albany, Schools, Public (3 of 3), 1933-1980; Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Albany, Schuyler Mansion, 1917-1977; Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Albany, Snow Show, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Albany, South End, 1961; 1964; 1966-1969; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Albany, Spanish Center, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Albany, Saint Margaret's House and Hospital for Babies, 1961; 1972; 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Albany, Saint Peter's Hospital, 1961-1964; 1966; 1971-1973; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Albany, Saint Peter's Hospital, 1963-1966; 1969; 1973-1974; 1979 (Oversized 2, Folder 39)
- Albany, Strategic Planning Committee, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Albany, Streets, 1936-1985; Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Albany, Streets, 1939; 1950; 1958 (Oversized 2, Folder 40)
- Albany, Streets, Lighting, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Albany, Streets, Lighting, 1966 (Oversized 2, Folder 41)
- Albany, SUNY, 1936; 1967-1970; 1980; Undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Albany, SUNY, Livingston Tower, 1968; Undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Albany, SUNY, Rockefeller Institute of Government, 1981-1982; Undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Albany Symphony Orchestra, 1958-1981; Undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Albany, Ten Broeck Mansion, 1937-1983; Undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Albany, Ten Broeck Triangle, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Albany, Ten Eyck Project, 1975; 1977 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Albany, Tercentenary Celebration, 1919-1929; 1964 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Albany, Thanksgiving Community Feast, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Albany, Theater and Theaters, 1936-1981; Undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Albany, Theater and Theaters, 1936; 1940; 1956 (Oversized 3, Folder 1)
- Albany Times Union, 1945-1947; Undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Albany Times Union, 95th Anniversary Edition, 1950 (Oversized 3, Folder 2)
- Albany Times Union, A Day in the Life of Albany, 1992 (Oversized 1, Folder 9)
- Albany Times Union, Dutch Albany, 2002 (Oversized 3, Folder 3)
- Albany Times Union, New York State Almanac, 1941 (Oversized 1, Folder 10)
- Albany, Tivoli Lakes, 1958; 1961-1962; 1965-1966; 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Albany, Transportation, 1936-1979 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Albany, Tricentennial, Calendar and Poster, ca. 1986 (Oversized 3, Folder 4)
- Albany, Tricentennial Celebration, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Albany, Tricentennial, Newspapers, 1983 (Oversized 1, Folder 11)
- Albany, Tricentennial, Newspapers (1 of 4), 1986 (Oversized 3, Folder 5)
- Albany, Tricentennial, Newspapers (2 of 4), 1986 (Oversized 3, Folder 6)
- Albany, Tricentennial, Newspapers (3 of 4), 1986 (Oversized 3, Folder 7)
- Albany, Tricentennial, Newspapers (4 of 4), 1986 (Oversized 3, Folder 8)
- Albany, Tri City Women's Center, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Albany, Trinity Institution, 1953; 1961; 1966; 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Albany, Tulip Festival (1 of 2), 1951-1981; Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Albany, Tulip Festival (2 of 2), 1951-1981; Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Albany, Tulip Festival, 1951; 1953-1955; 1958-1961 (Oversized 3, Folder 9)
- Albany, Twin Towers, 1973; 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Albany, Union Station, 1955-1985; Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Albany, Urban League, 1977; 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Albany, U.S. Bicentennial, 1973; 1975-1977; Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Albany, Van Rensselaer Manor, 1931-1961; Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Albany, Van Rensselaer Manor, 1955 (Oversized 3, Folder 10)
- Albany, Villa Mary Immaculate, 1959-1960; 1974; Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Albany, Voluntary Action Center, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Albany, Walsh House, 1959; 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Albany, Washington Park, 1936; 1962-1966; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Albany, Whitney M. Young Jr. Health Center, 1974; 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Albany Woman's Club, 1955; 1960 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Albany Women's Center, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Albany, Women's Conferences and Organizations, 1956; 1960-1964; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Albany, Women's Organizations, 1960 (Oversized 1, Folder 12)
- Albany, "World's Biggest Trophy Case?", 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Albany, Young Men's Association for Mutual Improvement, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Albany, YMCA, 1957 (Oversized 3, Folder 11)
- Albany, Youth, Problems, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Altamont, 1970-1972; 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Averill Park, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Ballston Spa, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Barge Canal, 1925-1979; Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Barge Canal, 1970-1980; Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 13)
- Berne, 1956; 1974 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Bethlehem, Description, 1956-1979; Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Bethlehem, Police, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Buffalo, 1966; Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Capital Area Community Health Plan, 1976-1979; 1981 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Capital District, Abortion, 1971; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Capital District, Actors, 1968; 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Capital District, Affirmative Action, 1974; 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Capital District, Amnesty International, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Capital District, Anti-ballistic Missiles, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Capital District, Antisemitism, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Capital District, Appalachian Trail, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Capital District, Archaeology, 1967; 1972 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Capital District, Archaeology, Industrial, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Capital District, Architecture, 1972; 1976; 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Capital District, Armenians, 1963; 1978 (Box 5, Folder 40)